module 10 tracking progress and feedback loops this is super important this might be one of the
most important modules just within this foundational course because like I had said at the forefront in
one of these modules if you don't understand the why your sales are doing well I don't know what
to shift some importance on if you don't know why your sales are doing bad you don't know what to
prioritize right so you want to be able to measure what matters I have a book here called measure what
matters just quick side note weekly scorecard metrics how many cold emails cold messages have
you sent what was the response rate if you sent 100 was it three so then hopefully you got one
client from that if not does that mean three responses led to zero sales how many responses
lead to sales right track this because then you'll know how many messages you got to start sending out
what does your engagement look like once they do reply are you being left on read so to speak right
are you emailing them and they email back and it took three days for you to reply because you have so
many you can't keep track of it you got you you have to have an analysis of what the numbers like funnel
into right that's the sale and you need to understand how many messages you sent how many started a
conversation from there how many actually talked about a sale and then finally you made the sale
you'll be able to replicate that system once you know those numbers measure all of that right and here
is an example of the the simple pipeline tracking this is your basic CRM that we had talked about of
might be live within your google sheets for now right um i messaged acme local dentist on instagram
that dm led to a negotiation and i already worked on what that contract will look like for this specific
use case or this is my boilerplate contract there's the value okay so on and so forth and that's literally
what it should look like in addition to obviously like maybe in that case their instagram handle
their email phone number um employee as well as their rank in the business right it is kind of
important if you're not talking to the decision maker how do you get there right and you'll start to
figure that out as well if you're talking to the um person at the front desk you're not gonna
let them make the decision right but you are gonna want to schedule with them so you can have
an actual conversation with the decision maker and who is that you're gonna have to figure that out
right and the quicker you can do all of those things the quicker the sale
building feedback loops this is uh going back to that repeatable process outreach prospects data
this is that tracking conversion rates right the funnel that we had talked about all those messages
funneled into the sales right clients review results and wins review on a weekly basis right review
um what that timeline looks like did it did you abide by week one week two week three week four
timelines did something get pushed back was that a consistent pushback at week three did you see that
where clients constantly complaining about the same thing across multiple um verticals like what
are you seeing consistently you can't always just be in the thick of it right or else you're gonna just
get bogged down and now you're you're working for a living you need to zoom out you need to have
the ability time and data to zoom out and look at what's working what's not working
diagnosed kind of the same thing fix right you're seeing the consistent um angry emails from your
client on week three why is that fix it right and then repeat
15 minute weekly review ritual this is just something that we like to do make sure this is a weekly thing
sometimes even a daily thing right maybe your daily uh routine needs fixing maybe your weekly routine
needs fixing maybe it's an internal fix maybe it's an external use this worksheet as a guide for
your feedback loop love this what to measure and why
we had talked about originally what is that sales metric is it just dollars in
or is it time spent emailing prospects is it time spent gathering prospect information is it time spent
finding the decision maker what is the problem identify it and somehow measure it right
i like this cannot force a yes but you can force 50 messages sent per week that's in your purview
okay and then key takeaways look over this um i'm gonna do another lesson here if you are still with me here
we'll go over exactly how um in seven days we can make at least a thousand dollars for your business okay
okay
you